

147 South Edgely Ave.. Toronto, ON M1N 3L3

e: jonathan.m.blackburn@gmail.com

w: http://jblackburn.comoj.com

t: 416-951-7088

Profile

- 14 years working experience in both a team setting and as an individual
- Full-stack developer: MySQL, php, angular js, jQuery, css, HTML5
- design patterns usage (MVC, Factory, Strategy, Singleton, Adapter, Decorator, Facade)
- data modeling, functional specification and development plan writing abilities
- firm belief in AGILE methodologies
- a love of learning (after all, experience only matters if I keep trying to improve & evolve my skills)

Selected Work Samples

Teletoon (2011 - 2014)

http://www.teletoon.com

Cartoon Network Canada (2012 - 2014)

http://www.cartoonnetwork.ca

Teletoon Retro (2013 - 2014)

http://www.teletoonretro.com/

Toon Feud (api developer, 2012 - 2014)

http://www.toonfeud.ca

Paul Hastings iPhone app (February 2010)

http://itunes.apple.com/sa/app/paul-hastings-janofsky-walker/id418535227?mt=8

Murdoch Mysteries (March 2009)

www.murdochmysteries.com

The website of the TV Series "Murdoch Mysteries", deployed in Canada and the UK.

Work Experience

Full-stack Senior Developer, TELETOON Canada Inc; Toronto - April 2011 - January 2014

As Senior Developer, I have built user-facing content, UGC modules, an API framework and a proprietary CMS for our three national network brands (Teletoon, Teletoon Retro and Cartoon Network) and two network blocks (Adult Swim Canada, Teletoon At Night). Reporting to the Technical Manager, I take on a wide variety of development tasks.

Notable Accomplishments:

- a php API that handles gameplay tracking, content rating, user polls, image galleries, activity tracking and special link tracking. It provides a single point of access to all callers, and returns data in a chosen format (preferably JSON, though sometimes XML and, for legacy content, string data)
- a range of site content modules such as: a platform game engine, deployed as two chapters of THWARP; an Avatar Builder (Actionscript 3), Scene Builder (jQuery), drag and drop contest entry mechanisms (jQuery), a Meme Generator framework (jQuery), a jQuery/Javascript State pattern that has been implemented in a number of contest / promotion microsites, as well as several of such sites when required
- a Content Management System that has allowed us to standardize our data structures across all of our sites, easily add and modify said data, and publish individual or groups of files to our sites. The main benefit of this approach is that we can rapidly create and deploy game and TV Show content, as well as execute bulk changes to our content in a very short period of time.
- all modules and systems, with the exception of Cartoon Network and Adult Swim, are bilingual

Flash/iPhone Developer, Panvista Media Corp; Toronto - August 2009 - April 2011

Developed a news reader (Actionscript 3) that could be deployed in any website, as well as a desktop AIR application for the community-based web publishing platform that was the business focus at the time. In early-mid 2010, Panvista shifted its focus to developing a mobile application platform and has sold into the Canadian & United States legal industries. My contribution was to develop an iPhone application framework, featuring a variety of display templates that can be customized with interchangeable navigation styles, transitions, and colour themes.

Developer, Kolody Inc; Toronto - 2006 - August 2009

Kolody Inc. specializes in developing feature-rich, textured Flash applications with robust back-ends to power them. As such, my roles switched between object-oriented Actionscript 3 web sites and php/MySQL development.

Developer, Teletoon Canada Inc; Toronto - 2004 - 2006

Developed Flash modules for teletoon.com (activities, contests, microsites) as well as php modules to manage content for the flagship site and thedetour.ca.

Interactive Designer, Marketspace Design Group; Toronto - 2002 - 2004

Designed and developed websites using largely client-side technologies (Flash, HTML, JavaScript, CSS).

Freelance Developer, Toronto - 2001 - 2002

Mostly brochure-ware and simple Flash game development.

Flash Developer, DECODE Entertainment Inc.; Toronto - 2000 – 2001

Developed site and Flash games for Angela Anaconda online property.

Skills

Core: php, MySQL, Actionscript 3 (including AIR), Javascript (jQuery & Angular.js), CSS, json

Complimentary: XML, Objective-C

Environments: Industry-standard authoring environments (Adobe, XCode) APIs / Integration: Brightcove, Amazon S3, Facebook, Twitter, Google Charts

Analytics: Google Analytics, Adobe SiteCatalyst

Other: Unit testing with GHUnit, version control (GIT, Source Tree), WinSCP, FTP, XAMPP, MAMP

Education

Ryerson University, Journalism (BAA) 1997

References

Available on request